Steven Wells

Senior Software Developer - java, web and integrations

swellz@pm.me

LinkedIn

GitHub

StackOverflow

PDF

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology (Computer Science & Software Engineering)

Griffith University 1993 - 1995

INTERESTS

Kayaking

Running

Cycling

Hiking

CAREER PROFILE

An experienced software developer that thrives in the process of producing the best system possible - underwritten by producing quality software.

Core competencies: Java and Web Generalist, databases, Integrations.

Industries: Procurement, Mining, TAB and Banking

Specialities: Java 8+, Groovy/Grails/Spock, Angular, SAPUI5, Scrum, SQL, XML/XSL

During my career I have been fortunate enough to engage in a broad range of technologies, people, experiences and industries.

Maintaining flexibility and having an open-minded approach to work has been key in developing an interesting and fulfilling career.

EXPERIENCES

Senior Business Process Consultant

Oct 2012 – Present SAP Ariba

Developed applications working and web-based tools that follow SAP Fiori design guidelines using UI5, JPA, Spring, Spock and Liquibase...a lot of Javascript and Java! Secondary skills include Angular, REST, OData, Jenkins, Git, Scrum and JIRA.

Key Responsibilites

- Develop web interfaces that comply with SAP Fiori design guidelines using SAPUI5
- Develop supporting backend services with Java as the primary tool
- Write test specifications unit and integration with Spock and Groovy
- · Maintain and write supporting documentation for developers and users
- Work and align with a truly global team leveraging Scrum
- Continually provide feedback on how the team can improve processes and practices

Key Acheivements

- Improved testing line coverage from 30% -> 75%. Recognised with an award as I drove this to a best practice mandatory task; ensuring developers not only accepted but enjoyed the process
- · Designed and deliver requirements for stakeholders on a regular release cycle with zero delays or errors
- · Flexibility, working with and understanding people from different cultural backgrounds, technical abilities and timezones.
- Ensured team documentation was up-to-date and accurate

Senior Software Engineer

April 2007 - Oct 2012

Quadrem - Ariba

Provide technical integration services and support between large resource companies and their suppliers. Implement internal systems to support integration processes (including Web 2/AJAX work and version control systems).

Key Responsibilites

- Development leader. Designed, managed and developed a suite of highly interactive "Web 2.0" applications using JQuery and Grails with connections to legacy databases
- Designed and developed behind-the-firewall solutions that enable customers to connect to the Quadrem and Ariba trading networks
- Worked with a global team to enhance the existing Enterprise Services platform
- Managed and documented interactions between all parties involved in an integration.
- · Onboarding and mentoring new team members.

Key Acheivements

- Development of automated testing framework using Angular and Grails. Increasing QA efficiency, coverage and output by at least 3 times
- Develop a round-trip system for an Ellipse buyer sending Purchase Order (includes Change Order) to the Quadrem
 marketplace and Invoice back in to Ellipse This was a ground-up development of an integration system based on Mulesoft and
 including a custom web interface (for admin and monitoring) to connection a Mincom Ellipse system.
- Maintenance and development of Webmethods integration services for a range of customers and geographic locations on a regular basis
- Developed demo system/adapters using .Net to connect to Quadrem with MYOB, successfully demonstrating Order/Invoice cycle from an MYOB (Order) to a Quadrem SupplyCentre supplier.

Developer/Architect

2002 - 2007

Rio Tinto

Software development and architecture supporting an EAI environment

Java Developer

2003 - 2004

LGAQ / Resolute IT

LDAP Conversions, Web Admin application - Java and Struts

Consultant - eCommerce

1999 - 2002

Deloitte Consulting

NAB Internet Banking + Java and SAP interfacing projects

Software Developer/Designer

1996 - 1998

TAB Old

Software developer
1996
Pace Autosystems Canada
GIS, C++, VB
Software developer
1995 - 1996 No.
Mincom
Delphi, Java, PERL developing SCM applications
PROJECTS
Other acheivements and projects
Grails Angular on Heroku tutorial - Diceware - how-to project with Grails and Angular hosted on Heroku with writeup:
https://medium.com/@wellsst/angular-with-grails-on-heroku-211e35177804
Solo hike across Switzerland - Solo hike across Switzerland, planning: https://sites.google.com/site/viaalpina2017/preparation
SKILLS & PROFICIENCY
Java
Javascript & jQuery
Angular
HTML5 & CSS
THINES & GOO
Grails
Groovy/Spock
Databases/SQL
Resume Steven Wells
1 COUNTY OF THE PROPERTY OF TH

Internet Betting - the first of its kind in Australia